<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J A C K</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on J A C K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>War for Rayuba - Searching the Exalted Plains</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-07-18-rayuba-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-07-18-rayuba-1/</guid>
      <description>Small skirmishes pepper the grassy plains near Team Bastion&#39;s home base. A lone sniper looks out.                                                                                                                         A polite and well dressed diversion, but Deeushan&amp;rsquo;s search continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco Whiplash (gallery)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-23-sf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-23-sf/</guid>
      <description>SF birds.           SF cars.           SF develops infrastructure.           SF moves around.           SF shows local pride.           SF signs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bike Kitchen serves a 5 course meal - building a bike from parts</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-12-01-scrap-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-12-01-scrap-bike/</guid>
      <description>The San Francisco Bike Kitchen is where you find mechanical magic. This local non-profit, run by volunteers, offers a build-a-bike program for $40. This lets you build a bike with the used parts lying around the Kitchen. From frames to wheels to handlebars, patience is all that&amp;rsquo;s needed to assemble a custom ride.
I fully intended to bike everywhere when I moved to SF, and even picked an apartment location that would let me do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Foldable Ukulele in the World</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-09-29-portable-uke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-09-29-portable-uke/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I started playing guitar at university and wanted to keep going when I moved around. My solution was to invest in a foldable Voyage Air guitar. It didn&amp;rsquo;t provide me with exactly the freedom and engineering satisfaction I was looking for: it was not truly foldable - it comes with a custom, oddly shaped backpack for carrying when packed away.
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve always dreamed about just sawing a ukulele in half to take it to the extremes with no compromises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adler Special Typewriter</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-07-26-adler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-07-26-adler/</guid>
      <description>A gift that the previous owners of my home left. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it until I watched the documentary California Typewriter on a flight! Brought it outside, cleaned it out, and now I have a nice, heavy, writing machine. I&amp;rsquo;m very lucky to have found it in working condition.
  This is the most similar model that I&amp;rsquo;ve found online, though the key labels seem slightly different. As a fan of mechanical keyboards already, using this typewriter is a joy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packing less is good for my soul</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-09-packingless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-09-packingless/</guid>
      <description>For the past 5 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved every 4 months. It&amp;rsquo;s taken time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve changed from a hoarder (the way of my people) to someone who wants very little. It was a gradual process, moving from 32&amp;quot; luggage to 28&amp;quot;, to a Kelty Redwing 50. I found myself cleaving away at my possessions with every move. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t use the vast majority of it and having stuff felt like a burden, mentally and physically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY camera finger strap to travel real light</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-07-fingerstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-07-fingerstrap/</guid>
      <description>I just bought a used Fujifilm X70 in an attempt to save on space and weight. To keep chasing that goal, I made another change. Neck strap -&amp;gt; wrist strap -&amp;gt; finger strap. This is my take with the material I had lying around. I trimmed a simple velcro strap from some knock-off go-pro kit, and fitted it by trial and error:
            Comfortable, adjustable, and surprisingly secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 9</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-05-fine229-b9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-05-fine229-b9/</guid>
      <description>Farah&amp;rsquo;s original work: https://minddrewablank.wordpress.com/2017/07/04/moving-still/
Herd is an image constructed from video sourced from Planet Earth. It compresses an overhead shot of a herd of animals into a single frame, creating a textured blur with sporadic details. Inspired by Corinne Vionnet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Photo Opportunities,&amp;rsquo; Farah&amp;rsquo;s piece mimics a long exposure photo using photoshop. The piece is dominated by soft browns and grays, with shadowy lines and blotches as the only recognizable features. Visually, it is well balanced and ambiguous, lacking constrasts and distinct shapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 8</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-04-fine229-b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-04-fine229-b8/</guid>
      <description>Deep remixability When previously separate mediums are being combined in various ways - not just by format, but by technique, culture, and other meta-characteristics as well.
## Variable form A motion graphic sequence that never holds all its aspects static for long - some part of it is constantly in flux at some point in time. ## Continuity turn The shift from discrete cuts and marked delimitations to continuous, gradual changes in motion graphic sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Game - statement</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-30-mental-game-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-30-mental-game-statement/</guid>
      <description>The Mental Game reflects a moment of tension that everyone has experienced before. As a child, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s jumping down more steps than you&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried. As a teenager, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s clicking &amp;ldquo;submit&amp;rdquo; on an application that will decide your future. As an adult, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s stepping into a class far out of your comfort zone. In a single moment, instinctual hesitation kicks in. Time seems to slow down and you feel separated from the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comic layouts in the digital age?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-29-mental-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-29-mental-game/</guid>
      <description>           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking pictures of moving things is hard</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-27-still/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-27-still/</guid>
      <description>   

She&amp;rsquo;ll never fall!   --    

Float   --    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 7</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-22-fine229-b7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-22-fine229-b7/</guid>
      <description>  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 6</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-17-fine229-b6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-17-fine229-b6/</guid>
      <description>Constructed Narrative When the contents of a photograph have been artificially created by the artist in some way to reflect a narrative, rather than simply photographing a real scene. An example is A Sudden Gust of Wind (after Hokusai), taken by Jeff Wall, portraying the same narrative as the woodcut that inspired the work. The photograph was constructed digitally from various pieces.
http://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks/wall-a-sudden-gust-of-wind-after-hokusai-t06951
## Tableau A photograph where the scene is assembled and actors are used to produce a certain result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A digital perspective - literally mixing media</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-12-digital-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-12-digital-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Camera and Microphone          Photos partially mixed with the audio recordings of the same moment, both kept in raw data formats.

Multiple Viewpoints   --    Importing and exporting funny business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A digital perspective - statement</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-12-digital-perspective-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-12-digital-perspective-statement/</guid>
      <description>Camera and Mic highlights the relationship between digital media and our physical senses. The piece prompts the viewer to recognize a pattern among 3 images.
The glitch highlights the eyes and ears to build an association with the title of the piece, suggesting that cameras and microphones imitate the eyes and ears. However, glitches are an explicit piece of evidence showing that these devices are not perfect. The presence of the glitches suggest a disconnect in how information is captured, though we frequently consume digital media as an illusionary extension of our own senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 5</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-08-fine229-b5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-08-fine229-b5/</guid>
      <description>
How obvious do you want it bro?    Composited with selection, levels, shadows, spot healing, and manual drawing. Originals:
  --       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 4</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-06-fine229-b4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-06-fine229-b4/</guid>
      <description>A world with people:    
And a world without:    ### Indexical A characteristic of images that implies a mapping to the original real world subject. Some relationship between the two is suggested, such as the chemical reactions driven by light reflected from a subject in film photography. This characteristic is debated in digital photography as physical interaction is less apparent, and converted into numerical data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Processing Pipeline - final architecture</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-02-data-pipeline-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-02-data-pipeline-3/</guid>
      <description>part 2
Configuration, security, and deployment with SQS were all as easy as expected, and IAM has been a great convenience. It was also pretty straight forward to write tasks for Celery - but successes are not interesting.
Celery does not play perfectly with SQS.
One source of struggle was having scheduled tasks, thanks to SQS limitations (mostly relating to timeouts). We were forced to use local scheduling solutions for timed output delivery - in this case, Advanced Python Scheduler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra glitches</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-02-fine229-glitches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-02-fine229-glitches/</guid>
      <description>An attempt to databend a .CR2 file (A-Law in Audacity). This kind of result seems to happen fairly consistently. Other attempts found on the internet seem to confirm this.
   Complete failure to databend .CR2 using U-Law in Audacity.
   A crash in Chrome. First time it has happened to me.
   A bug in my own program. I was re-coding the drawing logic for a game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Game - SunShower</title>
      <link>/blog/project-sunshower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-sunshower/</guid>
      <description>Play it!
Github
Pet project based on an idea I had for a simple, challenging game with a high skill ceiling. It&amp;rsquo;s basically Tetris 360. Original intention was to learn more about using a game framework and marketing.
Turns out I&amp;rsquo;m also learning a lot about game design, user feedback management, and Google Analytics. There are definitely still improvements (like row elimination animations) to be made and more marketing (like a dedicated domain) to be done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cans Cans Cans - glitch experimentation</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-28-cans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-28-cans/</guid>
      <description>Source image is a picture of Campbell&amp;rsquo;s Soup Cans, by Andy Warhol, found here: https://www.timeout.com/newyork/art/andy-warhol-campbells-soup-cans-and-other-works-19531967. Displayed images have all been converted to JPG for presentation.
    imported into Audacity from BMP applied Phaser effect to section of audio - rows of cans could actually be distinquished in the audio      imported into Audacity from BMP applied reverse effect to section of audio      imported into Audacity from photoshop RAW applied a Paul Stretch to section of audio re-imported RAW as an image with fewer channels, at a resolution of 1000 x 1000      imported into Audacity from photoshop RAW applied a pitch shift from F to D to section of audio re-imported RAW as an image with fewer channels, to riginal file size      opened BMP in text editor copy pasted random sections of text into different areas      exported from photoshop as interleaved RAW re-imported as a non-interleaved RAW iamge      exported from photoshop as interleaved RAW (3 channels) re-imported as interleaved RAW (10 channels)      imported into Audacity from photoshop RAW adjusted frequency levels on one section of the audio increased bass and decreased treble by 5 dB      imported into Audacity from photoshop RAW applied WahWah effect to one section of the audio      ripped USB out of computer while BMP file was transferring mystery finally solved  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-28-fine229-b3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-28-fine229-b3/</guid>
      <description>A Pure Glitch is an effect either produced without intention or without understanding the underlying cause and system. A Glitch-alike is an effect produced purposefully and with some form of reasoning about how the effect was created.
My attempts are shown in a separate post here.
### Datamoshing Datamoshing is an effect based on the visual presentation of compression artefacts found in lossy file formats. For this reason, they are often shown in certain common formats like GIFs, JPEGs, or video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with gifs - statement</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-23-gifs-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-23-gifs-statement/</guid>
      <description>Making Waves is a short story about a boat in the small fishing town of Lamu, Kenya.
Fishing has always been a mainstay in Lamu, but never the focus. It used to be a thriving port in the center of East African sea trade. Now it&amp;rsquo;s a UNESCO World Heritage site, relying on the tourism and investment of foreigners. However, the story isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet and nearby, one of the largest ports in East Africa is currently being built by Chinese corporations (Weitere).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The small fishing town of Lamu</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-22-gifs-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-22-gifs-2/</guid>
      <description>
Making Waves 
   

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 2</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-16-fine229-b2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-16-fine229-b2/</guid>
      <description>Stereography A technique to generate a sense of depth in a visualization by presenting a different image to each eye. Mimics the way humans naturally perceive depth in every day life. Various techniques have been used, ranging from mechanical devices working with film photographs to polarized light in a 3D movie. Can be a highly effective technique, but usually requires a fairly complex mechanism. This may affect the experience of the viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinemagraphs of an old African beach</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-11-gifs-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-11-gifs-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to make a cinemagraph since I first saw one on Reddit. The stars aligned: when I visited Lamu, I actually remembered. Keeping this in mind, I took a bunch of pictures in continuous shooting.
Realizing that creating a nice cinemagraph would be a lot of work, I first threw my pictures onto Google photos. The automatic &amp;ldquo;animation&amp;rdquo; utility would give a good preview for how they might look. Here&amp;rsquo;s how they turned out (slow loading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-10-fine229-b1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-10-fine229-b1/</guid>
      <description>Subjectivity An object that can be evaluated or interpreted differently by different subjects observing it.
An example is the series of portraits done by Guim Tió, where black and white portraits receive strokes of colored paint. The meaning of the added color is abstract and open to interpretation.
http://www.guimtio.com/no-name-project-2/
### Pictorial space The simulated sense of 3D space created by 2D artwork. This is commonly seen in the world of matte paintings, where realistic artwork is used as backdrops in film, often imitating large spaces that are too expensive to build a set for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why art</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-10-fine229-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-10-fine229-intro/</guid>
      <description>It was one of my favorite subjects, and I even did extra classes. But these were technical sessions and offered very little creative flexibility; I quit often. To scratch the itch I turned to art on my own time: http://malsatas.deviantart.com/.
Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that I like &amp;ldquo;doing art&amp;rdquo; because I enjoy creating and telling stories. I like building flavorful worlds and presenting compellling characters. I like the idea of reaching into people with stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Processing Pipeline - Amazon AWS SQS vs RabbitMQ benchmarks</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-21-data-pipeline-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-21-data-pipeline-2/</guid>
      <description>part 1
Our data pipeline needs a message broker for a Celery job queue; RabbitMQ and Amazon SQS are two good choices. They are designed to scale, guarantee message delivery, and seem to have good support.
RabbitMQ has a solid reputation as a broker, with diverse and robust features. It works very well with Celery. The only real disadvantage is that it relies on custom configuration and deployment. SQS is a message queue as a service, self-scaling and configurable from a web UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Pipeline - Requirements and architecture</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-20-data-pipeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-20-data-pipeline-1/</guid>
      <description>At my work, we&amp;rsquo;re building a pipeline to provide data-driven feedback to users.
The de-facto king for data is Python, thanks to its community. A common way to deploy these models is via a Flask application, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t a good fit for every case. What if the service doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a front end? What if clients don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait for a potentially long operation? What if our business requirements are still uncertain, and we anticipate a need to scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine for 3 winters in a row</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-19-All-the-warm-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-19-All-the-warm-places/</guid>
      <description>I have a great view of the grey tarmac and overcast sky from my seat on the turboprop. Taking off, above the clouds, it&amp;rsquo;s a hot, sunny day.
   Nairobi has hit rainy season and drops to a frosty 17 Celsuius overnight. Naturally, I&amp;rsquo;m taking a trip to the local island paradise on the coast, Lamu. I&amp;rsquo;m also leaving Kenya very soon &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;ve luckily escaped the dreary days right as they come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s hard to get used to losing things</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</guid>
      <description>Those of us that don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to history are doomed to repeat it.
1 year ago: I&amp;rsquo;m on exchange, and life is fun. We travel as if we could actually afford it. I have a waterproof camera, my trusty blue Panasonic Lumix TS5, because GoPros are way out of my budget. Next to cross off the list is Bali.
   We&amp;rsquo;re all excited to try surfing. I have a blast and learn that it&amp;rsquo;s really hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexa Skill - Daily Wiki</title>
      <link>/blog/project-wiki-daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-wiki-daily/</guid>
      <description>Amazon
Github
Yes I did it for the free Alexa dev sweater.
No I haven&amp;rsquo;t retrieved my sweater yet. The ratings are pretty bad. People want the entire featured article read out to them. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add that if I get the time. Feel free to make a pull request!
Fun to play with Node on AWS Lambda. Also learned about YQL queries, which seem pretty useful for web scraping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Net Powered Chrome Ext. - Page Predictor</title>
      <link>/blog/project-page-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-page-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Github
A chrome extension that predicts what website you&amp;rsquo;re going to &amp;mdash; so you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to type it in!
Our team&amp;rsquo;s base assumption is that we visit some websites in certain patterns, and a neural net might be able to pick up on them. Learning about normalizing data, recurrent neural networks and tweaking them. Admittedly, test results so far have been quite poor and we will probably try some different training methods or ways of preprocessing/cleaning the history data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Web App - Pattio (WIP)</title>
      <link>/blog/project-pattio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-pattio/</guid>
      <description>On social media, we don&amp;rsquo;t communicate the way we do in real life. There are different protocols and habits, which can make interactions feel shallow or distracting. We want to make an app that promotes meaningful and spontaneous conversations for close friends and family.
Important features include voice calls, seeing and joining ongoing conversations between friends, allowing guests to join, and less &amp;ldquo;indirect&amp;rdquo; engagement such as statuses and leaving messages. We also want to build a &amp;ldquo;binary indicator&amp;rdquo; culture - availability implies a genuine interest in spending time to chat, rather than ambiguous &amp;ldquo;busy&amp;rdquo; statuses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture shock is real if you take yourself far enough</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</guid>
      <description>Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
   &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely overwhelming&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; assurances come from many of the people I meet. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.
I landed after a 24 hour itinerary carrying my 50L backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTFM - software engineering 101</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</guid>
      <description>I thought I had found a flaw in the great google machine - instead I learned that &amp;ldquo;libraries are innocent until proven guilty&amp;rdquo;.
I am currently working on an app for Kenyan users, with validation for local phone numbers. We use google&amp;rsquo;s libphonenumber library. While testing, I realized that my Kenyan number was considered invalid.
I check the source code and searched for &amp;ldquo;kenya&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;Prefix 25476 added for Airtel Kenya based on open-source bug report [&amp;hellip;] other prefixes from Wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Board Game - Arimaa Free</title>
      <link>/blog/project-arimaa-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-arimaa-free/</guid>
      <description>Play Store
Github
Open source contributions welcome! I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for someone to pass on the development torch; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting work to be done, especially as a beginner/intermediate project. AI bots and online multiplayer! Send an email to jackthesong@gmail.com and I&amp;rsquo;d be glad to set you up/do a walkthrough.
Interestingly, a game designed to be difficult for computers to play. But AI players have very recently beaten humans!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Ext. - Morbid Motivation</title>
      <link>/blog/project-morbid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-morbid/</guid>
      <description>Chrome Store
Github
The idea is to use our inevitable passing as a source of motivation. Colours are configurable to the user&amp;rsquo;s tastes.
A fairly simple app made in a few hours for a short hackathon. An early attempt to learn ways of modularizing javascript code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiplayer Web App - Colorful Conway</title>
      <link>/blog/project-conway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/project-conway/</guid>
      <description>Try it live
Github
Different clients are given different colours on a standard Game of Life board. The simulation runs as usual - except new cells are generated as an average colour of the cells around it.
It was interesting to have to deal with the realities of network latency and a relatively inefficient computation. Signficant compromises had to be made to the original design. Simulations are round based rather than constantly running to allow the server to synchronize clients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
