<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack</title>
    <link>http://whoisjack.today/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://whoisjack.today/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shock</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/plane.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely overwhelming&amp;rdquo; - assurances came from many of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve met. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed after a 24 hour flight iterary carrying my 50L backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell if it was supposed to be a bribe and he didn&amp;rsquo;t even fill the form in correctly. I rushed into an Uber because the driver was yelling &amp;ldquo;faster, faster!&amp;rdquo; He laughed as we sped away. He said that a policeman was walking over, likely looking for trouble. While I unpack at my new home I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve caught a cold. The jet lag didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/road.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve had it rough but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been too bad, just unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture shock is real, and things are very different around here. There are power outages. There&amp;rsquo;s a drought - water outages. The faces I see everywhere are what not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. Private property is always gated and every mall enforces security checks. Doctors have been on a nation-wide strike for over a month now. These things reminded me that I was travelling and I took them in stride. Because I like travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the smaller things that tired me out. Being out of breath at the top of a staircase because it&amp;rsquo;s 1,600m above sea level. Wondering if the way I say &amp;ldquo;mambo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;asante&amp;rdquo; sound empty. Supressing my feelings of concern every time a soldier walks by with a rifle. These small things made me anxious for the next day. The anxiety was kind of fun, but this is not a vacation getaway, it&amp;rsquo;s a 4 month stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than usual, I&amp;rsquo;d want to spend some weekend days at home, doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/room.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that I would get used to it eventually. It felt like waiting for the day you finally feel better after being sick. I also knew that it could take a very long time, or never quite finish completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know when, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve already gotten used to most of it. I also realized that the expats I meet have already gone though a similar process, or are currently working through it. Some could be caught in much more difficult circumstances than what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Still, we probably have it relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire the millions of immigrants around the world going through this process right now; they have bet their livelihoods on it. They&amp;rsquo;re in a gamble to write personal legends. Stakes are high and enduring the shock of a new world is only a small part of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/house.jpg&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTFM</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I had found a flaw in the great google machine - instead I learned that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JakeWharton/status/806344184999399424&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;libraries are innocent until proven guilty&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on an app for Kenyan users, with validation for local phone numbers. We use google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googlei18n/libphonenumber&#34;&gt;libphonenumber&lt;/a&gt; library. While testing, I realized that my Kenyan number was considered invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I check the source code and searched for &amp;ldquo;kenya&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;Prefix 25476 added for Airtel Kenya based on open-source bug report [&amp;hellip;] other prefixes from Wikipedia.&amp;rdquo; I take a look and Wikipedia does not contain a prefix for my number. Everything made sense - my number was recently issued. There&amp;rsquo;s no way google has the resources to keep up with all the technical changes in the world - and certainly not in Kenya where documentation is poor and growth is fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I regretfully hammer out a horrific switch case method to validate phone numbers instead of using the library - we did not have time to wait for a fix. But as I go to file a bug report, I read the guidelines: &amp;ldquo;Is the issue reproducible using the demo? [&amp;hellip;] Your issue may be resolved by upgrading to the latest version of the library.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try my Kenyan number in the online demo. It&amp;rsquo;s valid. Searching the issues gives &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googlei18n/libphonenumber/issues/804&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. I rollback and update the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So even if you&amp;rsquo;re in a volatile domain - give the library the benefit of the doubt and first RTFM. I guess I could at least submit a change to Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An argument can also be made that in a domain &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; volatile, it could be wise to use a less strict form of validation in the first place, depending the importance of the features vs. handling illegal values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: A telecommunication giant using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/SafaricomLtd/posts/10156369539590084&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/safaricomltd/status/633134928536932352&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; as technical communication channels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least they&amp;rsquo;re responsive!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arimaa Free</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/arimaa-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/arimaa-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;image-set&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/arimaa-screen-1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/arimaa-screen-2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=email.com.gmail.songjiapei.arimaa&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-playstore&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Play Store
    &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button end&#34; href=&#34;http://github.com/jack-song/Arimaa&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a game designed to be difficult for computers to play. But AI players have very recently beaten humans! &lt;a href=&#34;http://arimaa.com/arimaa/&#34;&gt;The original Arimaa can be found here.&lt;/a&gt; (warning: not a modern website)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun to design a system for rewinding and replaying games move by move. I ended up using a string serialization for recording actions based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arimaa.com/arimaa/learn/notation.html&#34;&gt;standard notation&lt;/a&gt;. Despite being intimidating, it was also fun to generate the recursive set of legal moves for the UI. Not too proud of the &amp;ldquo;GameEngine&amp;rdquo; class though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colorful Conway</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/conway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/conway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/conway-blurb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Colorful Conway&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://colorfulconway-songjack.rhcloud.com/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-globe&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Try it live
    &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button end&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/jack-song/colorfulConway&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different clients are given different colours on a standard Game of Life board. The simulation runs as usual - except new cells are generated as an average colour of the cells around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to have to deal with the realities of network latency and a relatively inefficient computation. Signficant compromises had to be made to the original design. Simulations are round based rather than constantly running to allow the server to synchronize clients. Simulations also run slower to improve consistency between clients with varying computing power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morbid Motivation</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/morbid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/morbid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/morbid-blurb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Morbid Motivation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/morbid-motivation/kjpeibokdagajocicdijpeognkpccphj&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-globe&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Chrome Store
    &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button end&#34; href=&#34;http://github.com/jack-song/MorbidMotivation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to use our inevitable passing as a source of motivation. Colours are configurable to the user&amp;rsquo;s tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fairly simple app made in a few hours for a short hackathon. An early attempt to learn ways of modularizing javascript code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>