<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack</title>
    <link>http://whoisjack.today/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://whoisjack.today/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How it feels to be have poor judgement and butterfingers&amp;hellip; again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of us that don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to history are doomed to repeat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 year ago: I&amp;rsquo;m on exchange, and life is fun. We travel as if we could actually afford it. I have a waterproof camera, my trusty blue Panasonic Lumix TS5, because GoPros are way out of my budget. Next to cross off the list is Bali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/bali.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/bali.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all excited to try surfing. I have a blast and learn that it&amp;rsquo;s really hard. The water is cold and the waves are relentless. It&amp;rsquo;s tiring just to walk out to catch a breaker. Standing up, balancing, and then wiping out is one of the greatest thrills I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/surfings.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/surfings.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decide to bring my waterproof camera with me in my pocket. As I pull myself out of the water, it&amp;rsquo;s gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;denial&#34;&gt;Denial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I check my pockets. Nothing. But they&amp;rsquo;re really big pockets - maybe they&amp;rsquo;re deeper down there? I look back out at the sea. Maybe. I duck my head underwater and feel around. Just maybe, I lost the camera right here, in this exact spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anger&#34;&gt;Anger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow I&amp;rsquo;m an idiot. Why did I think this was a good idea? I slowly wade out to catch another wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bargaining&#34;&gt;Bargaining&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must be punishment for me being an ass on the mountain that night. What if I just search for the rest of the day? It&amp;rsquo;s not like the beach is that big, or the waves are that active, or the camera is blue. Trying to stand on my board, I wipe out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;depression&#34;&gt;Depression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lost so many pictures! Our entire group had photos on it and I&amp;rsquo;ve let the team down. Deep in their hearts, they&amp;rsquo;ll never forgive me. :&amp;lsquo;(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;acceptance&#34;&gt;Acceptance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow surfing was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/beach.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/beach.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the present: I&amp;rsquo;m taking a matatu to meet some Kenyan friends. It&amp;rsquo;s sunny in dry season Nairobi so I bring my sweet, sweet NASA hat. My old faithful has been with me ever since I fulfilled my dream of visiting the Kennedy Space Center during my second coop term. I wore the copper, denim, and leather with pride. The matatu is hot so I leave it on my lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/matatu.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/matatu.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I&amp;rsquo;m almost at my friend&amp;rsquo;s place, I notice that I don&amp;rsquo;t have it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;denial-1&#34;&gt;Denial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped it on the ground walking from the matatu right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anger-1&#34;&gt;Anger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I not notice it dropping from my lap? Why did I not just put in my bag? I stew as I walk back to where I got off, staring at the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/hills.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/hills.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bargaining-1&#34;&gt;Bargaining&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I kept taking matatu for the rest of the day, could I find the right one? Maybe if I wait here diligently, the driver will come back to give me my hat. The lady running the nearby fried banana stand asks if I&amp;rsquo;m ok. I cover up the pain and say I&amp;rsquo;m fine, I&amp;rsquo;m just checking if I&amp;rsquo;m on the right street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;depression-1&#34;&gt;Depression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That hat was amazing, I&amp;rsquo;ll never get the same one again. It was a loyal friend and I betrayed it. I even made a hat-trade with Adam Savage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/losing/savage.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/losing/savage.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;acceptance-1&#34;&gt;Acceptance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey this giraffe hat is pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 4 years of university, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to leave a lot of things behind. I brought only a carry-on for my 4 month stay in Kenya. I idolize the idea that all I need in life are my wits and skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lose a practical possession, I barely care. Though sometimes I struggle to cope, I try to treat losing sentimental items the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll lose my memories with or without trinkets to anchor them. I&amp;rsquo;m a forgetful person. Even as I write this post, I have to fabricate details. These hard earned stories will soon sink into the back of my mind, becoming an anonymous piece of me. And I will be distracted by a new story. Lose, forget, change &amp;mdash; and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Wiki</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/wiki-daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/wiki-daily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Jack-Song-Daily-Wiki/dp/B01N2MAHX5/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-chatbubble-working&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Amazon
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/jack-song/WikiDaily&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I did it for the free Alexa dev sweater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No I haven&amp;rsquo;t retrieved my sweater yet. The ratings are pretty bad. People want the entire featured article read out to them. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add that if I get the time. Feel free to make a pull request!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun to play with Node on AWS Lambda. Also learned about YQL queries, which seem pretty useful for web scraping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that wikipedia doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually have an API for their featured articles&amp;hellip; It was brutal working through solution iterations until I arrived at the current one. One candidate was parsing the Atom feed XML with an actual server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storing the daily queries would make this service much more efficient at the cost of some complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Predictor (WIP)</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/page-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/page-predictor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/jack-song/PagePredictor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A chrome extension that predicts what website you&amp;rsquo;re going to &amp;mdash; so you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to type it in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team&amp;rsquo;s base assumption is that we visit some websites in certain patterns, and a neural net might be able to pick up on them. Learning about normalizing data, recurrent neural networks and tweaking them. Admittedly, test results so far have been quite poor and we will probably try some different training methods or ways of preprocessing/cleaning the history data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattio (WIP)</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/pattio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/pattio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently our team&amp;rsquo;s Fourth Year Design Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On social media, we don&amp;rsquo;t communicate the way we do in real life. There are different protocols and habits, which can make interactions feel shallow or distracting. We want to make an app that promotes meaningful and spontaneous conversations for close friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important features include voice calls, seeing and joining ongoing conversations between friends, allowing guests to join, and less &amp;ldquo;indirect&amp;rdquo; engagement such as statuses and leaving messages. We also want to build a &amp;ldquo;binary indicator&amp;rdquo; culture - availability implies a genuine interest in spending time to chat, rather than ambiguous &amp;ldquo;busy&amp;rdquo; statuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our proposed solution is a progressive web app based on WebRTC - our stack so far uses node, react, docker, yarn, and webpack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shock</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/plane.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/shock/plane.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely overwhelming&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; assurances come from many of the people I meet. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed after a 24 hour itinerary carrying my 50L backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell if it was supposed to be a bribe and he didn&amp;rsquo;t even fill in my form correctly. I rushed into an Uber because the driver was yelling &amp;ldquo;faster, faster!&amp;rdquo; He laughed as we sped away. He said that a policeman was walking over and looking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I unpack at my new home I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve caught a cold. The jet lag didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/road.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/shock/road.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve had it rough but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been too bad, just unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture shock is real, and things are very different around here. There are power outages. There&amp;rsquo;s a drought, which means water outages. The faces I see everywhere are what not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. Private property is always gated and every mall enforces security checks. Doctors have been on a nation-wide strike for over a month now. These things reminded me that I was traveling and I took them in stride. Because I like traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The small things tired me out. Things like being out of breath at the top of a staircase because it&amp;rsquo;s 1,600m above sea level. Wondering if the way I say &amp;ldquo;mambo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;asante&amp;rdquo; sound empty. Supressing my feelings of concern every time a soldier walks by with a rifle. These things made me anxious for the next day. It was a fun kind of anxiety but this was yet another step up from the places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to before. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a weekend getaway and this new world would be home for four months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than usual, I wanted to spend some weekend days at home, doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/room.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/shock/room.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt like waiting for the day you finally feel better after being sick. Of course, I fought my instincts and pushed myself to make plans. I would adapt eventually. I also knew that it could take a very long time to get over, or that I might never adjust completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did stuff. I hiked, climbed rocks, and did yoga. I went to events, had dinners, and met people. I hung around the kitchen to make small talk with my roomates. I had beers and struck up awkward conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immersing myself in everything really pushed things along. As I saw more of the city and heard the stories of more people, I became comfortable. It also helped to realize that the expats I met have had similar experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not the only ones. Immigrating as a child, I&amp;rsquo;ve never given much thought to the feelings my family had to cope with and the courage they built. The small taste I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten still can&amp;rsquo;t begin to compare to their challenges. Knowing this, my admiration continues to grow for the millions of people going through this process right now. They&amp;rsquo;re in a gamble to write personal legends and some have bet their lives on it. Stakes are high and enduring the shock of a new world is only a small part of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/house.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/blog/shock/house.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTFM</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-01-24-RTFM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I had found a flaw in the great google machine - instead I learned that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JakeWharton/status/806344184999399424&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;libraries are innocent until proven guilty&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on an app for Kenyan users, with validation for local phone numbers. We use google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googlei18n/libphonenumber&#34;&gt;libphonenumber&lt;/a&gt; library. While testing, I realized that my Kenyan number was considered invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I check the source code and searched for &amp;ldquo;kenya&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;Prefix 25476 added for Airtel Kenya based on open-source bug report [&amp;hellip;] other prefixes from Wikipedia.&amp;rdquo; I take a look and Wikipedia does not contain a prefix for my number. Everything made sense - my number was recently issued. There&amp;rsquo;s no way google has the resources to keep up with all the technical changes in the world - and certainly not in Kenya where documentation is poor and growth is fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I regretfully hammer out a horrific switch case method to validate phone numbers instead of using the library - we did not have time to wait for a fix. But as I go to file a bug report, I read the guidelines: &amp;ldquo;Is the issue reproducible using the demo? [&amp;hellip;] Your issue may be resolved by upgrading to the latest version of the library.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try my Kenyan number in the online demo. It&amp;rsquo;s valid. Searching the issues gives &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googlei18n/libphonenumber/issues/804&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. I rollback and update the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So even if you&amp;rsquo;re in a volatile domain - give the library the benefit of the doubt and first RTFM. I guess I could at least submit a change to Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An argument can also be made that in a domain &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; volatile, it could be wise to use a less strict form of validation in the first place, depending the importance of the features vs. handling illegal values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: A telecommunication giant using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/SafaricomLtd/posts/10156369539590084&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/safaricomltd/status/633134928536932352&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; as technical communication channels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least they&amp;rsquo;re responsive!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arimaa Free</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/arimaa-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/arimaa-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;image-set&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/arimaa-screen-1.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/arimaa-screen-2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=email.com.gmail.songjiapei.arimaa&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-playstore&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Play Store
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://github.com/jack-song/Arimaa&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source contributions welcome! I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for someone to pass on the development torch; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting work to be done, especially as a beginner/intermediate project. AI bots and online multiplayer! Send an email to jackthesong@gmail.com and I&amp;rsquo;d be glad to set you up/do a walkthrough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a game designed to be difficult for computers to play. But AI players have very recently beaten humans! &lt;a href=&#34;http://arimaa.com/arimaa/&#34;&gt;The original Arimaa can be found here.&lt;/a&gt; (warning: not a modern website)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun to design a system for rewinding and replaying games move by move. I ended up using a string serialization for recording actions based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arimaa.com/arimaa/learn/notation.html&#34;&gt;standard notation&lt;/a&gt;. Despite being intimidating, it was also fun to generate the recursive set of legal moves for the UI. Not too proud of the &amp;ldquo;GameEngine&amp;rdquo; class though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colorful Conway</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/conway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/conway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/projects/conway-blurb.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/conway-blurb.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://colorfulconway-songjack.rhcloud.com/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-globe&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Try it live
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/jack-song/colorfulConway&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different clients are given different colours on a standard Game of Life board. The simulation runs as usual - except new cells are generated as an average colour of the cells around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to have to deal with the realities of network latency and a relatively inefficient computation. Signficant compromises had to be made to the original design. Simulations are round based rather than constantly running to allow the server to synchronize clients. Simulations also run slower to improve consistency between clients with varying computing power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morbid Motivation</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/projects/morbid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/projects/morbid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img 
    class=&#34;lazyload&#34; 
    src=&#34;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&#34; 
    data-src=&#34;/assets/projects/morbid-blurb.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/projects/morbid-blurb.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/morbid-motivation/kjpeibokdagajocicdijpeognkpccphj&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-android-globe&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Chrome Store
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;http://github.com/jack-song/MorbidMotivation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;ion-social-github&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Github
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to use our inevitable passing as a source of motivation. Colours are configurable to the user&amp;rsquo;s tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fairly simple app made in a few hours for a short hackathon. An early attempt to learn ways of modularizing javascript code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>