<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on J A C K</title>
    <link>/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on J A C K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shipping as a habit</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-17-public-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-17-public-notes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a lot of projects (3d printing, grooming habits, video calling), but don&amp;rsquo;t publish enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t do the last 5%, I don&amp;rsquo;t risk it for the biscuit, and I don&amp;rsquo;t get feedback. The only reliable way to build behavior is through habits. Shipping is certainly a behavior. The answer then, is to make shipping a habit.
I&amp;rsquo;ll commit to publishing a small thing every day, even if it&amp;rsquo;s a working note or reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packing less is good for my soul</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-09-packingless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-09-packingless/</guid>
      <description>For the past 5 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved every 4 months. It&amp;rsquo;s taken time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve changed from a hoarder (the way of my people) to someone who wants very little. It was a gradual process, moving from 32&amp;quot; luggage to 28&amp;quot;, to a Kelty Redwing 50. I found myself cleaving away at my possessions with every move. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t use the vast majority of it and having stuff felt like a burden, mentally and physically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine for 3 winters in a row</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-19-All-the-warm-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-19-All-the-warm-places/</guid>
      <description>I have a great view of the grey tarmac and overcast sky from my seat on the turboprop. Taking off, above the clouds, it&amp;rsquo;s a hot, sunny day.
   Nairobi has hit rainy season and drops to a frosty 17 Celsuius overnight. Naturally, I&amp;rsquo;m taking a trip to the local island paradise on the coast, Lamu. I&amp;rsquo;m also leaving Kenya very soon &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;ve luckily escaped the dreary days right as they come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s hard to get used to losing things</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-14-Losing/</guid>
      <description>Those of us that don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to history are doomed to repeat it.
1 year ago: I&amp;rsquo;m on exchange, and life is fun. We travel as if we could actually afford it. I have a waterproof camera, my trusty blue Panasonic Lumix TS5, because GoPros are way out of my budget. Next to cross off the list is Bali.
   We&amp;rsquo;re all excited to try surfing. I have a blast and learn that it&amp;rsquo;s really hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture shock is real if you take yourself far enough</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</guid>
      <description>Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
   &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely overwhelming&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; assurances come from many of the people I meet. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.
I landed after a 24 hour itinerary carrying my 50L backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
