<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Jack</title>
    <link>http://whoisjack.today/categories/life/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Jack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://whoisjack.today/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shock</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy embed&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/plane.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s overwhelming&amp;rdquo; - assurances from many of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve met. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came in hot, finishing a 24 hour flight iterary with my four-month-stay backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip (bribe? he didn&amp;rsquo;t even fill the form in correctly). I jumped really fast into an Uber because the driver was yelling &amp;ldquo;faster, faster!&amp;rdquo; He laughed as we sped away. He says that a policeman was coming, looking for trouble. While I unpack at my new home I realize I&amp;rsquo;m sick. The jet lag didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy embed&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/road.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve had it rough but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been too bad, just unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture shock is real, and things are very different around here. There are power outages. There&amp;rsquo;s a drought - water outages. The faces I see everywhere and every day are what not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. I pass through a security check for every property I step onto. Doctors have been on a nation-wide strike for over a month now. These things told me that I was travelling and I took them in stride. Because I like travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the smaller things that tired me out. Being out of breath at the top of a staircase because it&amp;rsquo;s 1,600m above sea level. Wondering if the way I say &amp;ldquo;mambo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;asante&amp;rdquo; sound empty. Containing my surprise every time I see a soldier with a rifle. These made the whole experience feel fresh and also made me anxious for the next day. The anxiety was kind of fun, but this is not a vacation getaway, or &amp;ldquo;travelling&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a flight out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than usual, I&amp;rsquo;d want to spend some weekend days at home, doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy embed&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/room.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that I would get used to all of it. It felt like waiting for the day you feel good after being sick in bed. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s already happened, or happening, but I can&amp;rsquo;t explain how or when. And I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve finally had a taste of what millions of people have bet their lives on. To write their own personal legends, some are willing to endure the shock of a new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy embed&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/house.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>