<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Jack</title>
    <link>http://whoisjack.today/categories/life/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Jack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://whoisjack.today/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shock</title>
      <link>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whoisjack.today/blog/2017-02-08-Shock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I know a little more about making jumps and taking hard landings.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/plane.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely overwhelming&amp;rdquo; - assurances came from many of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve met. They&amp;rsquo;re consistently impressed that I&amp;rsquo;m so new to the African continent. Expats and locals are the same. They&amp;rsquo;re excited for my stay here, and equally sympathetic about the culture shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed after a 24 hour flight iterary carrying my 50L backpack. I said no to a border official asking for a tip. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell if it was supposed to be a bribe and he didn&amp;rsquo;t even fill the form in correctly. I rushed into an Uber because the driver was yelling &amp;ldquo;faster, faster!&amp;rdquo; He laughed as we sped away. He said that a policeman was walking over, likely looking for trouble. While I unpack at my new home I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve caught a cold. The jet lag didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/road.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve had it rough but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been too bad, just unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture shock is real, and things are very different around here. There are power outages. There&amp;rsquo;s a drought - water outages. The faces I see everywhere are what not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. Private property is always gated and every mall enforces security checks. Doctors have been on a nation-wide strike for over a month now. These things reminded me that I was travelling and I took them in stride. Because I like travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the smaller things that tired me out. Being out of breath at the top of a staircase because it&amp;rsquo;s 1,600m above sea level. Wondering if the way I say &amp;ldquo;mambo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;asante&amp;rdquo; sound empty. Supressing my feelings of concern every time a soldier walks by with a rifle. These small things made me anxious for the next day. The anxiety was kind of fun, but this is not a vacation getaway, it&amp;rsquo;s a 4 month stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than usual, I&amp;rsquo;d want to spend some weekend days at home, doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/room.jpg&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that I would get used to it eventually. It felt like waiting for the day you finally feel better after being sick. I also knew that it could take a very long time, or never quite finish completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know when, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve already gotten used to most of it. I also realized that the expats I meet have already gone though a similar process, or are currently working through it. Some could be caught in much more difficult circumstances than what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Still, we probably have it relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire the millions of immigrants around the world going through this process right now; they have bet their livelihoods on it. They&amp;rsquo;re in a gamble to write personal legends. Stakes are high and enduring the shock of a new world is only a small part of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&#34;b-lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://whoisjack.today/assets/load.png&#34; data-src=&#34;/assets/blog/shock/house.jpg&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>