<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diy on Jack</title>
    <link>whoisjack.today/categories/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diy on Jack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="whoisjack.today/categories/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Portable Ukulele in the World</title>
      <link>whoisjack.today/blog/2021-09-29-portable-uke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whoisjack.today/blog/2021-09-29-portable-uke/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I started playing guitar at university and wanted to keep going when I moved around. My solution was to invest in a foldable Voyage Air guitar. It didn&amp;rsquo;t provide me with exactly the freedom and engineering satisfaction I was looking for: it was not truly foldable - it comes with a custom, oddly shaped backpack for carrying when packed away.
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve always dreamed about just sawing a ukulele in half to take it to the extremes with no compromises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adler Special Typewriter</title>
      <link>whoisjack.today/blog/2020-07-26-adler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whoisjack.today/blog/2020-07-26-adler/</guid>
      <description>A gift that the previous owners of my home left. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it until I watched the documentary California Typewriter on a flight! Brought it outside, cleaned it out, and now I have a nice, heavy, writing machine. I&amp;rsquo;m very lucky to have found it in working condition.
  This is the most similar model that I&amp;rsquo;ve found online, though the key labels seem slightly different. As a fan of mechanical keyboards already, using this typewriter is a joy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY camera finger strap</title>
      <link>whoisjack.today/blog/2018-06-07-fingerstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whoisjack.today/blog/2018-06-07-fingerstrap/</guid>
      <description>I just bought a used Fujifilm X70 in an attempt to save on space and weight. To keep chasing that goal, I made another change. Neck strap -&amp;gt; wrist strap -&amp;gt; finger strap. This is my take with the material I had lying around. I trimmed a simple velcro strap from some knock-off go-pro kit, and fitted it by trial and error:
        Comfortable, adjustable, and surprisingly secure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>